gardenweb.com 2019-12-25

# PRIVACY POLICY

_Welcome is an online platform dedicated to home renovation and design. Houzz brings together home professionals, sellers of home goods, homeowners, renters, and design enthusiasts. Through Houzz, people can find design ideas, advice, products, and services related to home renovation and design. We announced that Ivy joined the Houzz family in February 2018. Ivy provides interior designers, architects, and other professionals with tools to better manage their day-to-day business and workflow with their clients and vendors. Ivy is also designed to improve the design experience for clients, by allowing them to review project-related documents and pay invoices from professionals._

This Privacy Policy describes what personal information we collect, how we use this information, how this information may be shared, and what choices and rights you have with respect to this information. Access and use of our Platform is subject to this Privacy Policy.

Our “Platform” is made up of Houzz, Ivy, and other sites, apps, products, and services on which this Privacy Policy is posted and that are Houzz-branded or operated by the Houzz group, including our plug-ins, embedded content made available on other sites, and browser extensions.

The terms “we,” “us,” or “our” refer to Houzz Inc., a Delaware corporation and Houzz Shop LLC, a Delaware limited liability company. The "[Houzz group](https://help.houzz.com/s/article/Houzz-group?language=en_US)" refers to corporate affiliates of Houzz Inc. By “you,” we are referring to visitors and users of any part of our Platform.

## **1\. Collection of Information**

We collect personal information that you provide us, from third parties, and automatically when you use our Platform. We collect information associated with your device using cookies and similar technologies. We may also receive information about your location.

### **Information You Provide Us**

We collect information that you provide us, including your account and profile information, content you submit or post to our Platform, your purchase information, your communications, and information you provide to us as part of surveys and contests.

**Account and Profile Information.** When you create an account on our Platform, we collect information you provide us, like your name, email address, interests, gender, age, and profile information. If you are a professional, you may also provide us information related to your business, including a business description and areas served.

**Content You Submit.** We collect information and content that you submit, post to, or create in our Platform, including your photos, comments, reviews, searches, photo notes, ideabooks, discussions, project details and costs, style preferences, and as a professional, other types of content provided for in our Houzz Pro or Ivy business management tools. 

**Purchases.** If you purchase or sell products or services or make or receive payments within our Platform, we collect certain information in order to complete your purchases, sales, and payments, such as your phone number, address, and payment method (for example, credit card or bank account information). If you participate in our Trade Program or Business Program, you may be asked to provide proof that you are eligible for the program or for a tax exemption.

**Communications.** When you communicate with us (via email, phone, through our Platform, or otherwise) and when you use our Platform to communicate with others, we may record, monitor, or otherwise collect details about your communications (including call time, and call duration). Certain professionals and sellers on our Platform may choose to use our call tracking feature in order to better manage their business. You are using our Platform when you make calls to these professionals and sellers using their phone number displayed on our Platform. We will provide you notice or obtain your consent in accordance with applicable law before recording or monitoring any of these calls. Otherwise, to the extent you communicate with professionals, sellers, and other users outside our Platform, those communications are not subject to this Privacy Policy.

**Surveys and Contests.** If you participate in our surveys, contests, or promotions, we will collect the information you provide to us.

### **Information from Others**

We collect information that others make available to us, including information from other platforms, publicly available information, information from other users of our Platform, information from our partners, service providers, and corporate affiliates, and information from third-party sites.

**Other Platforms.** We may receive information about you from third-party platforms when you allow the third-party platform to share this information with us or allow Houzz to obtain this information from the third party. For example, you may sign-up for our Platform through Facebook, Google, or Apple; upload your contacts from your third-party email service; use our Platform (or a third-party integration on our Platform) to manage your calendar on another platform or to manage and send communications (e.g., email or text messages).

**Publicly Available Information.** If you are a professional or seller, we may collect information about you from publicly available sources and where permitted by applicable law or with your permission, make it available as part of our Platform. For example, we may receive your name and contact information from industry associations and dealer networks in which you participate and display your affiliation with these organizations. We also may collect and display the details of any license you have using publicly available records.

**Other Users and Customers.** Others may post content on our Platform that includes information about you (for example, as part of photos, stories, and reviews) or provide us your information in connection with using our Platform (e.g., to manage their business, organize photoshoots of their projects, participate in referral programs, and to advertise through our Platform). In order to enhance the quality of our Platform, professionals and sellers on our Platform may provide us information about your engagement with them, including whether you have contacted them or responded to them, whether your project has been completed, and whether you have received a product you have ordered. If you are a professional or seller, Platform users and visitors may provide us with feedback and public reviews about you.

**Our Partners and Service Providers.** We may receive information about you from our partners and service providers. For example, our payment processors may update your payment information, advertising partners may help us send communications to your address, and third parties may help us prevent fraud by verifying your contact information. In addition, our banking partner that issues the Houzz credit card(s) may provide us with information regarding whether you have such a card, related to any card reward or loyalty program, or resulting from prescreening you for card offers.

**Houzz Group.** Subject to the privacy policies of our corporate affiliates and in accordance with applicable laws, we may receive information about you from them.

**Third-Party Sites.** Certain third-party sites embed a Houzz plug-in, widget, or content, including through Houzz-branded buttons, badges, and slideshows and Houzz co-branded content partnerships. Our plug-ins, widgets, embedded content, and pixels may collect information pursuant to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.houzz.com/cookiePolicy). You may also choose to use our browser extensions, which collect the information described in this Privacy Policy like the rest of our Platform. 

**Site Designer Websites.** Certain professionals' sites are developed or hosted by us (“Site Designer Website”). As with the rest of our Platform, we collect the information described in this Privacy Policy on the Site Designer Websites, including your messages to the professionals sent through those sites. These professionals collect usage information for their Site Designer Websites and receive your messages sent through those sites.

### **Automatically Collected Information**

Each time you access the Platform, information is sent to our server by your Internet browser or app and stored in our log files. We collect information about your use of our Platform, including your search activity, the pages you view, the date and time of your visit, and if you use our browser extensions, the content you interact with on third-party sites (for example, if you save an image from a third-party site to your Houzz account), and how you navigate and interact with a page or screen. We also collect information that your device provides to us in connection with your use of our Platform, such as your browser type, type of device, browser language, IP address, mobile carrier, unique device identifier, and requested and referring URLs.

### **Cookies and Similar Technologies**

We use cookies and similar technologies in connection with your use of our Platform to collect information related to what you see and interact with on our Platform and other Platform access and use. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.houzz.com/cookiePolicy) for more information on our use of cookies and how to accept or opt-out of cookies, but please note that unless required by law, we do not change system behavior within our Platform in response to browser requests not to be tracked.

### **Location Information**

We will receive your device's location if you enable this through your browser or mobile device. We may infer your general location from your IP address. You may also choose to provide us your location information by inputting this information in our Platform, including in your Houzz settings, Ivy settings, or when you checkout as a shipping or billing address.

## **2\. Use of Information**

We use the personal information we collect to provide, support, and personalize our Platform and to communicate with you about our Platform (on and off our Platform). The ways we do this include the following:

  * to provide and improve our Platform and its features and functionality, including to display content you post publicly, fulfill your purchases through our Platform, process, store, and deliver your communications; to provide customer service and support; to respond to your inquiries or requests; to back-up our systems; and to improve the security of our Platform;
  * to evaluate use of our Platform for our business purposes and to provide and improve our products and services, including new and co-branded products and services and our Platform's functionality;
  * to personalize your experience, such as tailoring the content and information made available to you and our support services;
  * to display relevant advertising (on our Platform and third-party sites) for us and other businesses and to evaluate the success of such advertising;
  * to provide feedback to professionals and sellers on our Platform;
  * to communicate with you as described in our agreements with you (for example, the Houzz [Terms of Use](https://www.houzz.com/termsOfUse)) or this Privacy Policy;
  * to prevent fraud and to maintain a quality experience for our business purposes or legal reasons, including to filter for spam and communications that violate our agreements with you (for example, the Houzz [Terms of Use](https://www.houzz.com/termsOfUse));
  * to enforce compliance with our agreements with you (for example, the Houzz [Terms of Use](https://www.houzz.com/termsOfUse)) and applicable law; to comply with our legal obligations; to prosecute or defend a lawsuit, arbitration, or similar legal proceeding; to respond to lawful requests by public authorities (including national security or law enforcement requirements);
  * to perform research and analysis for our business purposes; and
  * to award badges and similar designations and if you decide to participate, to administer surveys, contests, and promotions.

If you provide us information about your contacts (for example, when you sign up for our Platform through Facebook), in order to facilitate a more connected experience, we may inform your contacts who have accounts on our Platform that you also have joined our Platform and follow them on your behalf so that you may view their public activities on our Platform.

We may use your communications generally for quality assurance purposes and training and to improve our products and services. We may use your communications to understand and help manage the quality of requests received, and responses sent, by professionals and sellers on our Platform and to provide them with feedback. We may use automated technology to review your communications and improve user experience. [Learn more](https://help.houzz.com/s/article/Automated-Communications-Technology?language=en_US).

We may use your log-in information, cookie information, device information, IP addresses, and other information to identify you and log your use across devices, our Platform, and third-party sites. We may use this information to personalize your experience on our Platform.

For your convenience, we and our payment processors will store information about the payment method you use in connection with the Platform. Note that while our payment processors may store your complete credit card number, Houzz does not. You may remove or change your payment method on Houzz through your [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced). If you would like to change your payment method on Ivy and you use a credit card, please go to your Ivy [settings](https://members.ivy.co/designers/account_info). For your security, however, if you use ACH to make payments on Ivy, we may need you to contact support@ivy.co.

If you make purchases on Houzz as a visitor and subsequently create an account, for your reference, we will make information available to you about any prior purchases completed using the email address for your account.

If you are a client on Ivy, we use your information to show you all of your payments, as well as invoices, proposals, retainers, and similar documents on a per-project basis.

Any use of your information that is incompatible with these uses will be disclosed to you in advance so that you may opt out of, or agree to, such uses at your discretion.

## **3\. Sharing Your Information**

We do not rent or sell your personal contact information (such as your email address associated with your account registration) to third parties to use for their direct marketing purposes. We share personal information in the following ways:

### **Platform Visitors and Users**

One of the main purposes of having a Houzz account is to share home renovation and design ideas with others. Through Houzz, others have the ability to find, contact, view, and follow your profile and public activity on Houzz (for example, if you "like" content on our Platform or if you create an ideabook and do not mark it private) and link it to your username. You can customize your Houzz profile and whether users may follow you through your Houzz [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced). Other than your proprietary content that you generate in or upload to our Houzz Pro or Ivy business management tools, your Houzz content (for example, ideabooks, photos, notes on others' photos, projects, discussions, and social media profiles), followers, and others you follow are publicly viewable on the Platform and open to comments by other Houzz users. [Learn](https://help.houzz.com/s/article/How-do-I-adjust-my-privacy-settings?language=en_US) how to make these private. You also may choose to make certain information public on our Platform like your city and neighborhood. If you are a professional or seller on Houzz, we may also display the following information in order to help visitors and users evaluate you: your last visit to Houzz, aggregated information on our Platform about your Platform activity (e.g. response rate), and information that is publicly available from third parties. We have policies that place restrictions on Platform visitors' and users' use of information and content you choose to make available publicly through the Platform.

### **Professionals, Sellers, and Other Businesses on our Platform**

If you request us to find professionals for you, your project information (including the contact information) that you provide will be made available to a limited number of professionals that we believe may be suitable for your project. Professionals and sellers that participate on the Houzz Platform may view your public activities on our Platform and receive feedback you provide to us about your engagement with them. For example, if you requested us to find professionals for you and provide us feedback about your level of interest in these professionals, we may convey such feedback to them. In addition, a professional or seller can view your public activities on our Platform that are interactions with their content (for example, that you added one of their photos to your non-private Ideabook on a particular date, as identified by the username for your profile and any photo or public identifiers you provide for your profile). The business cannot see your non-public account information (for example, email address) or see private activity (for example, if your ideabook is private). We ask professionals, sellers, and advertising businesses on our Platform to limit the use of your information to the reasons for which the information was provided. 

### **Service Providers and Partners**

We may share your information with service providers and partners as reasonably needed for our uses described in this Privacy Policy. We ask our service providers to limit their use of that information for use on behalf of Houzz and for improving their services and products (in a de-identified form if legally required). You can find more information [here](https://help.houzz.com/s/article/Service-Providers-and-Platform-Partners?language=en_US) about our service providers and partners with which we may share your information. Only if you specifically agree to share your contact information with a third-party partner, for example, as part of a contest or promotion we sponsor with such third party, will we share your contact information with that third-party partner for their direct marketing purposes.

In addition, we may share information about you with third-party platforms when you allow the third-party platform to receive this information from us or allow Houzz to share this information with the third party. Our Platform may include third-party social media features and other third-party plug-ins and widgets. When these features are displayed on our Platform, they are operated or hosted by third parties and are subject to their own privacy policies instead of this Privacy Policy. For example, you may sign-up for our Platform through Facebook, Google, or Apple. 

### **Advertisers and Ad Networks**

We use advertising networks and partners to serve advertisements for us and other businesses, including interest-based advertising, on third-party sites and to assist us in evaluating the effectiveness of our advertising. We may also work with advertising networks and partners to serve ads on our Platform and to communicate with you at the addresses they have for you. We may provide advertising networks, advertising partners, and businesses advertising on our platform with aggregate information but other than hashed information or device identifiers, we do not disclose your name, contact information, or other personal information. For example, we may provide a hashed version of your email address or other information to advertising networks (e.g., Facebook and Google) to serve advertisements to you or others. To opt-out of the use of your information for this purpose, please send a request as provided under the Contact Us section.

We and the businesses advertising on our Platform, advertising networks, and advertising partners may also use cookies or similar technologies to track your activities on our Platform and other online properties in order to provide you with tailored ads across websites, apps, and devices and to understand how those ads perform. To learn how to opt-out of receiving this type of advertising, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.houzz.com/cookiePolicy).

### **Corporate Affiliates and Business Transfers**

We may share information from or about you with (a) joint ventures or other companies in the Houzz group, or (b) a potential or actual acquirer, successor, or assignee as part of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets, or stock (including in bankruptcy or similar proceedings). In these cases, their use will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

### **Legal Obligations**

We may disclose information from or about you, as required or permitted by applicable law, if we believe that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us, a service provider, or a partner (which may include disclosure to law enforcement, courts, or governmental authorities); (b) prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with our Platform; (c) protect our rights, reputation, property, or that of our visitors, users, corporate affiliates, or the public; or (d) enforce compliance with our agreements with you (for example, the Houzz [Terms of Use](https://www.houzz.com/termsOfUse)).

## **4\. Communications**

An essential part of our services that you sign up for when you create an account on our Platform is to receive communications from the Houzz group through email and our Platform. If you use our mobile app or provide us with your cell phone number, these communications also include text messages and push notifications. We communicate with you about your account, privacy, and interactions with your content (for example, if others "like" your Ideabook, respond to your comment, or if you earn a badge on our Platform). We also ask for your feedback about your experience in connection with our Platform or about your home renovation and design plans. In accordance with applicable law, we may send you marketing communications (e.g., with tips, offers, and similar services) from the Houzz group. These communications may feature us, our Platform, co-branded products and services, professionals, sellers, and other businesses on our Platform.

If you provide us your phone number, we may call and otherwise contact you to help you with using the Platform (e.g., to discuss your home remodeling or design project, to find professionals, or to assist with your order or if you are a professional, to find products or to provide you tips about your professional profile). If you are a professional or other business, we may use your contact information (whether publicly available or provided to Houzz) to call and otherwise contact you about our Platform, including to market and sell our products or services or those available on our Platform.

You may change your communication preferences at any time through your Houzz [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced) if you have a Houzz account and your Ivy [settings](https://members.ivy.co/designers/account_info) if you have an Ivy account, and you may also opt-out of similar types of marketing emails from us directly through the email. To opt-out of our text messages at any time, you can follow the instructions provided in the text message, which typically is to reply “STOP.” You may opt-out of sales and marketing phone calls from us by letting us know during the call or by contacting us as described in the Contact Us section. Your communication preferences on Ivy and Houzz are independent and generally will not affect or change the communications you receive through the other portions of the Platform. Please be aware that you cannot opt-out of receiving account- and privacy-related messages from us. If you wish to stop receiving push notifications from us, you can turn off push notifications for the mobile application in the settings of your mobile device.  
Our Platform also allows you and others to send messages and make calls in our Platform, share content with others outside our Platform, and if you make your contact information available, for others to contact you outside of our Platform.

## **5\. Your Choices and Rights**

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. We may ask you to verify your identity in order to help us respond to your request securely and efficiently.  
Even where not legally required, we will use reasonable efforts to complete requests to access or delete your personal information. You may request to receive a copy of your Houzz information through your Houzz [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced). You may access both your Houzz and Ivy information by contacting us as provided in the Contact Us section. To request permanent deletion of your personal information, please contact us as described in the Contact Us section.  
To edit your personal information, you can manage your profile on our Platform, as well as your Houzz [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced) and Ivy [settings](https://members.ivy.co/designers/account_info). You may also contact us about correcting or updating your personal information (including your marketing preferences) using the methods provided in the Contact Us section. We will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.

## **6\. Account Termination and Data Retention**

Unless you are a professional or seller on Houzz, you can deactivate your Houzz account at any time by going to your Houzz settings. To deactivate your account as a professional or seller on Houzz, please contact us as described in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy. To deactivate your account on the Ivy Platform, please follow the instructions [here](https://help.ivy.co/en/articles/1115070-how-can-i-cancel-my-ivy-membership) or contact us as described in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy. When you deactivate your account, you will cease to provide ongoing or future data to us that is associated with your account. Your Houzz profile will no longer be accessible on the Platform but in accordance with applicable law and the Houzz [Terms of Use](https://www.houzz.com/termsOfUse), your photos, reviews, and other content may still be available through our Platform. In order to request permanent deletion of the personal information associated with your account, please contact us as described in the Contact Us section.

We will keep your personal information only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we are processing your personal information unless the law permits or requires us to retain your personal information for a longer period. For example, we may need to keep your personal data for quality assurance purposes for our Platform or to defend future legal claims. We also will retain de-identified information after your account has been deleted. Information you have shared with others will remain visible after your account has been deactivated or deleted and after the information has been deleted from your own profile or account. We do not control information or content that others have copied out of our Platform. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified, or deleted may continue to reside in our systems for a period of time, and we may maintain copies of this information as part of our business records.

## **7\. Children**

Our Platform is intended for general audiences and is not directed to children under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16, we will take appropriate steps to delete that information. If you become aware or believe that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact us as provided in the Contact Us section.

## **8\. Data Security**

We use reasonable and appropriate measures to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the personal information.

## **9\. Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of our Privacy Policy will govern our use of information about you. If we make material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email or by posting a notice on our Platform or by other means, to offer you an opportunity to review the changes before they become effective. By continuing to access or use our Platform after those changes become effective, you are subject to the revised Privacy Policy.

## **10\. Contact Us**

Within the Houzz group, Houzz Inc. is responsible for the use of your personal information. If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy (including about the manner in which we or our service providers treat your personal information), you may contact us in the following ways:

  * If you are an Ivy user, please email us at support@ivy.co;
  * if you are a Houzz user and a resident of the European Economic Area, please email us at EUprivacy@houzz.com;
  * otherwise, if you are a Houzz user, please email us at privacy@houzz.com.

You may also reach our Chief Privacy Officer by mailing us at our address at 285 Hamilton Avenue, Palo Alto, California 94301, USA, Attn: Chief Privacy Officer or by emailing privacy@houzz.com, Attn: Chief Privacy Officer. 

## **11\. International Transfers of Personal Information**

The Houzz group is a global organization, headquartered in the United States, with service providers, corporate affiliates, and operations in several countries. In order to provide you with the services you sign up for by creating an account or visiting our Platform, your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States (or any other country where we, our corporate affiliates, agents, and service providers operate). Data protection laws differ among jurisdictions, and the United States and these other jurisdictions may not provide the same level of protection for personal information as your jurisdiction of residence. For example, your information may be required to be disclosed to law enforcement or government authorities under the laws of those jurisdictions. If you are from the European Economic Area ("EEA") and we transfer your personal information to countries outside of the EEA, we will take appropriate steps to ensure your personal information is afforded the same level of protection as described in this Privacy Policy. If you are located in the EEA or Switzerland, we comply with all legal requirements for the transfer of personal information to countries outside of the EEA or Switzerland. [Learn more, including about our participation in the Privacy Shield Frameworks](https://help.houzz.com/s/article/Privacy-Shield-Frameworks?language=en_US).

## **12\. Additional Information for Individuals from the European Economic Area**

If you are from the EEA, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. We collect and use your information for a variety of business purposes that are in our legitimate interests, in order to enter into or perform a contract with you, with your consent, or to comply with our legal obligations.

If we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

If you wish to learn more about specific legal grounds we rely on to process your information for any particular purpose (including any legitimate interests we have to process this information), please contact us as provided under the Contact Us section. For example, we rely on our legitimate interests to process information for direct marketing purposes and for fraud prevention and detection, provided these interests are not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.

Houzz takes reasonable steps to ensure that the data we collect is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and up to date. In addition to the rights described in the Your Choices and Rights section, you have additional rights in relation to your personal information, including the right to object to, or to ask us to restrict, the processing of your personal information. You can exercise these rights by contacting us as provided in the Contact Us section. You also can deactivate your Houzz profile through your Houzz [settings](https://www.houzz.com/settingsAdvanced) and deactivate your Ivy account following the instructions [here](https://help.ivy.co/en/articles/1115070-how-can-i-cancel-my-ivy-membership).

You can complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information in relation to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable law. For more information, and to submit a GDPR complaint, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the EEA and Switzerland are available [here](https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080).

## **13\. Additional Information for Individuals from California**

This section will provide specific information for California consumers to address the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) by January 2020. 

Effective January 1, 2020
